SOLUTION ARCHITECT · CLOUD ARCHITECT · DEVOPS · TECH LEAD

725, Sector 14, Gurugram, Haryana - 122002

🛮 (+91) 9660100100 | 🗷 me@anandvyas.in | 🍪 anandvyas.in | 🖸 anandvyas | 🛅 anandvyas | 🐧

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

### **Summary**<sub>-</sub>

Having more than 11+ years of vast professional experience in IT and 2 years AWS experience as an AWS Solution Architect. Working with various technologies like AWS Web Services, Nodejs, Angularjs, PHP, Drupal, Codeigniter, CakePHP, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Redis, Memcache, JSON, API. As a Solution Architect/Technical Architect/Team Lead in various phase of career gained excellent client and team handling ability. Using this skill to communicate directly with the client and perform the best as a team. Also, have involved and contributed a lot in converting the requirements into effective business design. Always been a part of Release Process and Stage Maintenance.

**Skills**: AWS Cloud Architect, VPC, EC2, S3, SNS, SQS, ELB, Auto Scaling, Cloud Front, Docker, Vagrant, Git, Jenkins, Linux, Redis, Javascript, Node.js, Php, Drupal, MySQL, ElasticSearch

# Work Experience

Srijan Technologies.

Delhi, IN

SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT & TECHNICAL ARCHITECT

June 2015 - PRESENT

- Architect, design and implement solutions with AWS Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2), Elastic Load Balancer (ELB), AutoScalling, RDS, S3, CloudWatch and other AWS products.
- Ensure success in building and migrating applications, software and services on the AWS platform.
- · Participate in deep architectural discussions to ensure solutions are designed for successful deployment in the cloud.
- · Communicate with the stack holders internally and externally at various level to identify existing IT infra and future need.
- Involved in knowledge sharing and technical guidance to the team members.
- Deployment of code and database on staging and production servers.
- Implementing GIT, CI based workflows in our projects.
- · Participate in the Sprint planning process.
- · Performing hands on development when needed.

Cyberlinks Technologies Gurugram, IN

TECHNICAL ARCHITECT / TEAM LEAD

June 2014 - June 2015

- Leading Teams of 2 8 people in successfully delivering projects
- Mentoring the team members
- Ensuring the timely and Quality delivery of projects.
- Working closely with the Project Manager / Business Analyst in understanding requirement and breaking them down.
- Participate in the Sprint planning process and provide breakdown and effort of tasks.
- Working closely with a Mobile Team to develop Web Services and APIs
- Hands on development with the team to deliver web projects
- Deployment and maintenance of developed Web applications

Arcgate Technologies Udaipur, IN

ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL ARCHITECT / TEAM LEAD

May 2012 - May 2014

- Leading Teams of 2 6 people in successfully delivering projects
- Mentoring the team members
- Ensuring the timely and Quality delivery of projects.
- · Working closely with the Project Manager / Business Analyst in understanding requirement and breaking them down.
- Participate in the Sprint planning process and provide breakdown and effort of tasks.

**Arcgate Technologies** 

Udaipur, IN

Sr. Developer May 2008 - May 2012

- Developed and maintain PHP/MySQL, Cakephp, Drupal, Wordpress, Nodejs and Javascript based applications.
- Defining best practices for project support and documentation.
- Handling application development as well as unit, integration and system testing.
- · Identifying technical & functional requirements / pain areas & mapping the same in line with organizational needs.
- Designing & developing database objects like tables, views, and procedures.
- Coding & Review as per Coding guidelines issued by the client.
- Writing APIs which are used by Mobile Apps or any other platform.
- · Consuming APIs of various third party services.

Rajasthan Patrika JAIPUR, IN

DEVELOPER Feb 2007 - May 2008

- Deployment and maintenance of Rajasthan Patrika website.
- Deployment and maintenance of news integration support backend tools.
- Compare with other news sites and new features.

Acro Computing India HYDRABAD, IN

TRAINEE / DEVELOPER Jun 2006 - Feb 2007

• Trained in PHP, MySQL concepts and its working. Also, got training as a System engineer.

## **Certifications**

Oct 2017 AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, Z8KHJR1111441LW8

Sept 2017 AWS Certified Developer - Associate, FBVPWNDCCME1QF99

Sept 2017 AWS Certified SysOps Administrator - Associate, ECPZTLHCKJQ1QMCE

AWS

AWS

AWS

## **Education**

#### Master in Computer Application (M.C.A)

RAJASTHAN UNIVERSITY (A+ BY NAAC, INDIA)

July 2003 - Aug. 2006

Rajasthan, IN